myidcare.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy

_Updated 11/30/2016_

Identity Theft Guard Solutions, Inc. doing business as ID Experts complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from European Union member countries.   ID Experts has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.  If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

ID Experts uses its best efforts to respect the privacy of online visitors. ID Experts does not collect personal information (such as name, address, e-mail address, or phone number) unless you voluntarily provide the information or are a member in ID Experts' Identity Theft program. For example, if you have questions about ID Experts' services, you may provide your e-mail address, and a response to your inquiry will be sent to that e-mail address. You do not need to register or provide information to view some sections of this site; however, only members enrolled in the ID Experts Identity Theft program may login to the Member Site section. If you are a participant, ID Experts will ask you to give us your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, and other information. ID Experts will only request and use the information necessary to administer the program.

ID Experts is committed to maintaining privacy and security controls over the information that you provide. ID Experts uses appropriate security safeguards and encryptions to protect your information. ID Experts uses passwords, security questions, and other applicable security measures to prevent an inappropriate entity or individual from gaining access to or knowledge of your data. ID Experts cautions its members and others to be aware that cell phones and email messages are not secure means of transmitting personal information.   Please note that ID Experts may be required to disclose personal information in response to a lawful request by law enforcement authorities including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

ID Experts acknowledges the individual’s right to access their personal data.  EU individuals wishing to inspect, edit, or delete their personal information may do so by:

**Email Request to:**

Privacy Officer at [privacyofficer@idexpertscorp.com](mailto:privacyofficer@idexpertscorp.com)

**Mail Request to:**

Privacy Officer

ID Experts

10300 SW Greenburg Rd, Ste 570

Portland, OR  97223

Access to your personal information by ID Experts employees is restricted to the employees who are providing you with the products and services offered by ID Experts. ID Experts shares personal information with third parties such as credit bureaus only if you authorize it by enrolling into monitoring services, where required by law, and only with the business affiliates that work with ID Experts to provide our products and services to you. ID Experts has agreements with its business affiliates that require them to maintain the confidentiality of any personal information sent to them. In addition, ID Experts requires that they use that information only for the specific and limited purposes related to providing ID Experts products and services, and that they have in place the necessary security standards (approved by ID Experts) to maintain the privacy and security of your personal information.  ID Experts may be liable for the appropriate transfer of personal information to third parties.

The ID Experts Web site uses a feature of your web browser known as a "cookie," which is a small text file that gathers non-personal information to facilitate access to and use of the site. "Cookies" also allow recognition of repeat visitors, track the pages visited, and collect data to help continue to improve the site. ID Experts does not use cookies for other purposes and does not share the information gathered by the cookies with third parties. Most browsers include a feature that allows the user to accept or deny cookies.

ID Experts may make changes to its Privacy Policy from time to time. Changes to the Privacy Policy will be posted to this Website and shall remain posted for a period of 2 months.

**Contact Information** In compliance with the EU Privacy Shield Principles, ID Experts commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact ID Experts at:

ID Experts

Attn: Privacy Manager

10300 SW Greenburg Road, Suite 570

Portland, OR 97223

Email: [PrivacyOfficer@idexpertscorp.com](mailto:PrivacyOfficer@idexpertscorp.com)

Please do not use e-mail to send information to ID Experts that you regard as confidential.

ID Experts is further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint.

Finally, and under certain limited conditions, EU individuals may invoke binding arbitration as a last resort before the Privacy Shield Panel.

The Company is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission.
